Guide to the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Oral History Collection, 2004
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Oral History Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Oral History Collection, 1973-1979 2004
24-04-3349
Laura Finkel
.4 cubic ft.
audio tapes, cd's.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Recordings of College of Veterinary Medicine events and individual oral history interviews.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Oral history project begun in 1973 by Ellis P. Leonard for use when writing history of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The project consists of 25 audio cassettes, 26 master copy CD's, and 26 service copy CD's. These interviews were conducted with veterinarians, faculty of the NYS College of Veterinary Medicine, and others regarding the development of veterinary medicine and practice in the United States as well as recollections of events in the history of the NYS College of Veterinary Medicine at Cornell University. Those interviewed include Donald W. Baker, Bruce Calnek, Randall Cole, H. H. Dukes, Morris Erdheim, Stephen Ettinger, Julius Fabricant, Robert Ferber, Robert Habel, Philip P. Levine, Jeanne Logue, Joseph Logue, Floyd C. Sager, Fred Scott, Robert Wasserman, Luella Williams, Alexander Winter, and Elmer Woelffer. Interviewers include Laura Finkel, J. Griffith, and Susanne Whitaker.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Baker, Donald Wyckoff, 1899-; Calnek, B. W.; Cole, Randall Knight, 1912-; Dukes, H. H. ?q (Henry Hugh), 1895-; Erdheim, Morris.; Ettinger, Stephen J.; Fabricant, Julius, 1919-; Ferber, Robert.; Habel, Robert E., 1918-; Levine, Philip P.; Logue, Jeanne.; Logue, Joseph.; Sager, Floyd, 1894-; Scott, Fredric W.; Wasserman, R. H. ?q (Robert Harold), 1926-; Williams, Luella.; Winter, A. J.. (Alexander J.), 1931-; Woelffer, Elmer.; Leonard, Ellis P., interviewer.; Finkel, Laura, ?c interviewer.; Griffith, J., interviewer.; Whitaker, Susanne, interviewer.
Subjects:
Veterinary medicine Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audiocassettes.; CD-Rs.; CD-ROMs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Available Copies:
Audio cassette tapes
CD's
PROVENANCE
Recordings made by Ellis P. Leonard; Suzanne Whitaker; and Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
each genre filed together
SERIES LIST
Series I. AUDIO TAPES
Box 1
Series II. CD MASTER COPIES
Box 1
Series III. CD USE COPIES
Box 1
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. AUDIO TAPES
  - tr8132a: Donald W. Baker; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1975 (Box 1)
  - tr8133a-tr8134a: Bruce Calnak; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8135a: Randall Cole; interviewer: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8136a: Arthur Gordon Danks; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1979 (Box 1)
  - tr8137a: H. H. Dukes; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1973 (Box 1)
  - tr8138a: Morris Erdheim; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8139a: Stephen Ettinger, "The Five Veterinarians I Met On the Way to Heaven," lecture CVM, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8140a-tr8141a: Julius Fabricant; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8142a: Robert Ferber; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8143a-tr8146a (2 copies of each): Robert Habel; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8147a: P. P. Levine; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1978 (Box 1)
  - tr8148a-tr8150a: George Poppensiek; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8156a, Side A: Floyd C. Sager; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1974 (Box 1)
  - tr8151a: Fred Scott; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8152a: Robert Wasserman; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8132a, Side B: Luella Williams; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1975 (Box 1)
  - tr8153a-tr8154a: Alexander Winter; interviewer: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - tr8155a, tr8156a, Side B: Elmer Woelffer; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1978 (Box 1)
- Series II. CD MASTER COPIES
  - CD 83: Donald W. Baker; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1975 (Box 1)
  - CD 84-85:Bruce Calnak; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 86: Randall Cole; interviewer: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 87: CVM Alumni Association, recorded by Ellis P. Leonard, 1985 (Box 1)
  - CD 88:Arthur Gordon Danks; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1979 (Box 1)
  - CD 89: H. H. Dukes; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1973 (Box 1)
  - CD 90:Morris Erdheim; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 91: Stephen Ettinger, "The Five Veterinarians I Met On the Way to Heaven," lecture CVM, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 92-93: Julius Fabricant; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 94:Robert Ferber; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 95-96:Robert Habel; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 97: P. P. Levine; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1978 (Box 1)
  - CD 98: Jeanne Logue and Joe Logue; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 99-101: George Poppensiek; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 102: Floyd C. Sager; interviewer: Ellis P. Leonard, 1974 (Box 1)
  - CD 103: Fred Scott; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 104: Robert Wasserman; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 105: Luella Williams; interviewer: Ellis P. Leonard, 1975 (Box 1)
  - CD 106-107: Alexander Winter; interviewer: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 108: Elmer Woelffer; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1978 (Box 1)
- Series III. CD SERVICE COPIES
  - CD 109: Donald W. Baker; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1975 (Box 1)
  - CD 110-111:Bruce Calnak; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 112: Randall Cole; interviewer: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 113: CVM Alumni Association, recorded by Ellis P. Leonard, 1985 (Box 1)
  - CD 114:Arthur Gordon Danks; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1979 (Box 1)
  - CD 115: H. H. Dukes; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1973 (Box 1)
  - CD 116:Morris Erdheim; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 117: Stephen Ettinger, "The Five Veterinarians I Met On the Way to Heaven," lecture CVM, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 118-119: Julius Fabricant; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 120:Robert Ferber; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 121-122:Robert Habel; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 123: P. P. Levine; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1978 (Box 1)
  - CD 124: Jeanne Logue and Joe Logue; interviewer: Laura Finkel, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 125-127: George Poppensiek; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 128: Floyd C. Sager; interviewer: Ellis P. Leonard, 1974 (Box 1)
  - CD 129: Fred Scott; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 130: Robert Wasserman; interviewers: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 131: Luella Williams; interviewer: Ellis P. Leonard, 1975 (Box 1)
  - CD 132-133: Alexander Winter; interviewer: Laura Finkel and Jeannie Griffith, 2004 (Box 1)
  - CD 134: Elmer Woelffer; interviewer: E. P. Leonard, 1978 (Box 1)